Thomas Foxen Anderson Papers 1928-1989 Mss.Ms.Coll.75
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1932-1989; 15 boxes; 7.5 linear feet
  - Philadelphia Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Phillips, Arthur P., 1946 (Box 11)
  - The Henry Phipps Institute, 1941 (Box 11)
  - Physical Techniques in Biological Research, 1955-1965 (Box 11)
  - The Physiological Society of Philadelphia, 1945, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Pirie, N.W., 1949-1950, 1970 (Box 11)
    -See also Ser.I, Gak, Ernst F.
  - Pitelka, Dorothy, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Pittman, David, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Pizer, Lewis, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Plenum Publishing Corporation, 1968-1970 (Box 11)
  - Plotz, Harry, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Plumb, Mary Ellen (Molly), 1958-1959 (Box 11)
  - Pollack, Sidney, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Pollard, J.W., 1978 (Box 11)
  - Pollard, Morris, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Porter, Keith R., 1945-1974 (Box 11)
    Claude, Albert
    -See also Ser.I, Conference on the Control of Form in Cells
    -See also Ser.I, Palade, George
  - Posternak, Jean, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Posternak, Yvonne, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Prater, Charles Dwight, 1950, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Pratt, David, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Prebus, A.F., 1943 (Box 11)
  - Pressman, David, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Presuhn, August, 1953 (Box 11)
  - Preuss, Luther E., 1957 (Box 11)
  - Price, Zane H., 1965-1966 (Box 11)
  - Prince, Alfred M., 1967-1968 (Box 11)
    Bayer, Manfred E.
    Blumberg, Baruch S.
  - Princeton University, 1942, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 1965-1988 (Box 11)
  - Protoplasmatologia, 1953-1957 (Box 11)
  - Puck, Theodore T., 1954, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Purdue University, 1940 (Box 11)
  - Putnam, Frank, 1954 (Box 11)
  - The Quarterly Review of Biology, 1974 (Box 11)
  - Radiation Research, 1955 (Box 11)
  - Radiography and Clinical Photography, 1945 (Box 11)
  - Ramachandran, G.N., 1967 (Box 11)
  - Raman, C.V., 1939 (Box 11)
  - Ramberg, Edward, 1944 (Box 11)
  - Randall, J.T., 1954 (Box 11)
  - Rapin, Annette Mary Coe, 1969-1971 (Box 11)
  - Rappaport, Catherine Fowler, 1951-1954, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Rappaport, Harry Porter, 1951-1962 (Box 11)
  - Rawlins, T.E., 1943 (Box 11)
  - Ray, James H., 1953, n.d. (Box 11)
  - RCA Laboratories, 1942-1953 (Box 11)
    Zworykin, V.K.
  - Reanney, Darryl C., 1978 (Box 11)
  - Rees, A.L.G., 1944 (Box 11)
  - Regional Conference on Electron-Microscopy in Asia and Oceania, 1956 (Box 11)
  - Reichman, M.E. (Box 11)
  - Reid, Roger D., 1955-1956 (Box 11)
  - Reisner, John H., 1986 (Box 11)
  - Rémond, Antoine, 1949-1955 (Box 11)
  - Revel, Jean-Paul, 1974 (Box 11)
  - The Review of Scientific Instruments, 1945-1946, 1953 (Box 11)
    -See also Ser.IV, The Physics of Viruses
  - Reynolds, Orr E., 1955 (Box 11)
  - Rhoades, Marcus M., 1972 (Box 11)
  - Rhoads, Jonathan E. (Box 11)
    -See Ser.III, National Research Council
  - Rice, Robert V., 1955 (Box 11)
  - Richards, A. Glenn, Jr., 1941, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Richter, Hans, 1951 (Box 11)
    in German
  - Riggs, Arthur D., 1968 (Box 11)
  - Rigney, David Roth, 1985-1986, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Rinker, J.N., 1956 (Box 11)
  - Rivers, Thomas M., 1941-1942 (Box 11)
  - Roberts, Edith A., 1942 (Box 11)
  - Roberts, Richard, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Robertson, J. David, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, John (Box 11)
    -See Ser.I, Fernandez-Moran, H.
  - Rochow, Ted G., 1962 (Box 11)
  - The Rockefeller Institute, 1957 (Box 11)
    Bronk, Detlev W.
  - Rodes, V.H., 1953 (Box 11)
  - Roess, Louis C., 1942 (Box 11)
  - Rohm and Haas Company, 1969 (Box 11)
    Ou, Jonathan T.
  - Rosen, Sid, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Rosenbluth, Walter A., 1967 (Box 11)
  - Rosenow, E.C., 1942 (Box 11)
  - Rosenthal, Harold W., 1962 (Box 11)
  - Rousselot, Albert, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
    -See also Ser.I, Kornblueh, Igho H.
  - Rubenstein, Irwin, 1961 (Box 12)
  - Rubin, Martin, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Rüdenberg, Reinhold (Box 12)
    -See Technology and Culture
  - Rudin, Donald O., 1961 (Box 12)
  - Rudkin, George T., 1973 (Box 12)
  - Ruhe, David S., 1943, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Ruska, Ernst, 1954-1958 (Box 12)
  - Ruska, Helmut, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Rutgers University the State University of New Jersey, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Ryan, Francis J., 1958 (Box 12)
  - Sadeh, Tsvi (Box 12)
    -See Ser.I, Stekol, J.A.
  - Sager, Ruth, 1977 (Box 12)
  - The Salk Institute for Biological Studies, 1964 (Box 12)
    Dulbecco, Renato
  - Sanford, William C., 1969 (Box 12)
  - Satir, Peter, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Sato, Gordon, 1954-1956, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Scanning Electron Microscope Symposium, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Schachter, David, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Schaechter, M., 1961 (Box 12)
  - Schaefer, Dale W., 1974 (Box 12)
  - Schaeffer, Pierre, [1954], 1978 (Box 12)
    -See also Ser.I, Hotchkiss, Rollin D.
  - Schlesinger, R. Walter, 1943 (Box 12)
  - Schmitt, Francis O., 1941, 1955 (Box 12)
    -See also Ser.I, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
  - Schoenfeld, Robert L., 1966 (Box 12)
  - Schroeder, Leslie R., 1942 (Box 12)
  - Schull, William J., 1971 (Box 12)
  - Schultz, Helen R., 1972-1976, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Schultz, Jack, 1958 (Box 12)
  - Science, 1945-1967 (Box 12)
    Glass, Bentley
  - Scientific American, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Scott, Gordon H., 1942 (Box 12)
  - Séchaud, Janine, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Secunda, Gloria, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Seiler, Karl, 3rd, 1942-1944 (Box 12)
  - Sellers, Margret I., 1957 (Box 12)
  - Servin-Massieu, Manuel, 1962 (Box 12)
  - Seymour, Francis I., 1941 (Box 12)
  - Shahn, Ezra, 1966, 1973, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Shemin, David, 1945 (Box 12)
  - Sheppard, David E., 1960 (Box 12)
  - Shilling, C.W., 1953 (Box 12)
  - Siegel, Benjamin M., 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Sigma Xi, 1942 (Box 12)
  - Silberberg, Donald H., 1971 (Box 12)
  - Silverstein, Saul J., 1985 (Box 12)
  - Silvestri, Luigi G., 1950 (Box 12)
  - Siminovitch, Louis, 1963, 1965, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Simon, Lee D., 1965-1979 (Box 12)
    Fernholm, Bo
    -See also Ser.I, Fernholm, Bo
  - Simon, Melvin I., 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Simpson, William L., 1958-1959 (Box 12)
  - Singer, Jacques M., 1959 (Box 12)
  - Singer, S.J., 1973 (Box 12)
  - Sinsheimer, Robert L., 1958 (Box 12)
  - Sivin, Nathan, 1960-1961 (Box 12)
  - Six, Erich W., 1960 (Box 12)
  - Sjöstrand, Fritiof S., 1953-1957, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Sjukhusdirektionens Bakteriologiska Centrallaboratorium, 1957 (Box 12)
  - The Skin and Cancer Hospital of Philadelphia, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Skoog, Folke, 1967 (Box 12)
  - The Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, 1953, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Smadel, Joseph E., 1942, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Smethurst High-Light Limited, 1954-1955 (Box 12)
  - Smith, Arthur R., 1972 (Box 12)
  - Smith, C.M., 1942 (Box 12)
  - Smith, Jackson Bruce, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Smith, Kenneth M., 1967 (Box 12)
  - Smith, Lucile, 1966-1978, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Société Française de Microscopie Électronique, 1963 (Box 12)
    Van Heyningen, W.E.
  - Society of the Sigma Xi, 1953, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Sognnaes, Reidar F., 1955 (Box 12)
  - Sonneborn, Tracy M., 1978; 2.0 Item(s) (Box 12)
    Molecular genetics; National Academy of Sciences; Protozoan genetics; Zinder, Norton D.
  - Sorof, Sam, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - South Jersey Medical Research Foundation, 1962-1965 (Box 12)
  - Southwell, W., 1960 (Box 12)
  - Spaulding, Earle H., 1972 (Box 12)
  - Speyer, Joe, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Spielman, Clair, 1966 (Box 12)
  - Springer, Georg F., 1964 (Box 12)
  - Springer-Verlag, 1953-1962 (Box 12)
  - E.R. Squibb and Sons, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Stanford University, 1958 (Box 13)
  - Stang, Louis G., Jr., 1965 (Box 13)
  - Stanier, Roger, 1957 (Box 13)
  - Stanley, W.M., 1940-1956 (Box 13)
    Mudd, Stuart, 15 Feb. 1941
  - Stanton, Frederick William, 1965-1966, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Stay, Barbara (Box 13)
    -See Ser.I, Larsen, Joseph R.
  - Steffens, Carsten, 1941 (Box 13)
  - Steinbach, H.B., 1943 (Box 13)
  - Stekol, J.A., 1963 (Box 13)
    Sadeh, Tsvi
  - Stent, Gunther S., 1958-1969, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Stephens, Richard, 1972, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Stern, Curt, 1972-1973; 7.0 Item(s) (Box 13)
    Bibliographical matters -- Schultz, Jack; Biographical and personal data -- Schultz, Jack; California Institute of Technology; Morgan, Thomas Hunt; National Academy of Sciences; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Stern, Kurt G., 1940, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Stocker, Bruce, 1957-1962 (Box 13)
  - Stone, Ronald, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Stowell, Robert E., 1958 (Box 13)
  - Streisinger, George, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Stuhlman, Otto, 1943 (Box 13)
  - Suito, Eiji, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Sunderlin, C.E., 1950 (Box 13)
  - Survey of Sources for the History of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Sutton, Richard M., 1943, 1953 (Box 13)
  - Suyama, Yoshitaka, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Swerdlow, Max, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
  - Sylvania Link No. 41 - Order of the Golden Chain, 1961-1962 (Box 13)
  - Symonds, Neville, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Symposium on Fundamental Cancer Research, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Symposium on Landmarks in Basic Biomedical Research, 1976-1977 (Box 13)
  - Szybalski, Waclaw, 1959, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Takahashi, I., 1961 (Box 13)
  - Tan, C.C., 1985 (Box 13)
  - Taylor, Austin L., 1973 (Box 13)
  - Taylor, J. Herbert, 1977 (Box 13)
    -See also Ser.I, Columbia University
  - Technology and Culture, 1960 (Box 13)
    Rüdenberg, Reinhold
  - Temin, Howard M., 1981 (Box 13)
  - Temple University, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Terada, Masanaka, 1954 (Box 13)
  - Terasima, Toyozo, 1955-1956 (Box 13)
  - Tereba, Allan, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Tessman, Irwin, 1958 (Box 13)
  - The Texas Company, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Thomas, Daniel, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Thorell, Bo, 1957 (Box 13)
  - Thorogood, Elizabeth, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Tikhonenko, A.S., 1968 (Box 13)
  - To, Sam C.M., 1970, 1976 (Box 13)
  - Tobacco Industry Research Committee, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Tobias, Cornelius A., 1966-1967 (Box 13)
  - Torrey, John Gordon, 1961 (Box 13)
  - Tousimis, A.J., 1959 (Box 13)
  - Truog, E., 1940-1941 (Box 13)
  - Tsichlis, Philip N., 1985-1986 (Box 13)
  - Turnbull, T.P., 1954, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Turner, James N., 1978-1981 (Box 13)
  - Tyson, Robert L., 1953 (Box 13)
  - Uchida, H., 1956 (Box 13)
  - Umbreit, W.W., 1941-1942 (Box 13)
  - UNESCO, 1952 (Box 13)
  - Unidentified, 1941-1976, n.d. (Box 13)
  - United States. Department of Commerce. Office of Technical Services, 1949 (Box 13)
  - United States. Department of the Navy, 1953 (Box 13)
  - United States National Committee for Pure and Applied Biophysics, 1964-1967 (Box 13)
  - University of Chicago, 1936-1963 (Box 14)
    Zirkle, Raymond E.
  - University of Illinois, 1959 (Box 14)
    Borasky, Rubin
  - The University of Michigan, 1964-1966 (Box 14)
  - University of Minnesota, 1940 (Box 14)
  - The University of North Carolina, 1986-1987 (Box 14)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 6 folders (Box 14)
    - Folder #1, 1942-1963 (Box 14)
    - Folder #2, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
    - Folder #3, 1966-1968 (Box 14)
    - Folder #4, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
    - Folder #5, 1971-1981, n.d. (Box 14)
    - National Science Foundation Academic Year Institute, 1958-1961 (Box 14)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1953 (Box 14)
  - University of Southern California, 1944, 1960-1961 (Box 14)
  - The University of Tennessee, 1941 (Box 14)
  - The University of Texas, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
  - University of Virginia, 1968-1970 (Box 14)
  - The University of Wisconsin, 1941, 1956 (Box 14)
  - The University of Wyoming, 1972-1973, 1975 (Box 14)
  - van Dorsten, A.C., 1952, 1953, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Van Heyningen, W.E. (Kits), 1949-1955 (Box 14)
    -See also Ser.I, Society for General Microbiology
  - van Iterson, Woutera, 1955 (Box 14)
  - van Niel, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Van Valkenburg, Robert J., 1961 (Box 14)
  - Van Vunakis, Helen, 1958 (Box 14)
  - Vande Woudl, George, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Vatter, Albert, 1953 (Box 14)
  - Vestling, Carl S., 1959 (Box 14)
  - Virology, 1955-1968 (Box 15)
    Black, Lindsay M.
  - von Borries, Bodo, 1950, 1955-1956 (Box 15)
  - Wacker, Waldon B., 1987 (Box 15)
  - Wagner, Robert P., 1968 (Box 15)
  - Waksman, Selman A., 1942 (Box 15)
  - Wald, George, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Walker, Donald H., Jr., 1961-1974 (Box 15)
    Hartman, Philip E.
    Kim, Sun Kee
    Melechen, Norman E.
  - Walker, S.R.B., 1942 (Box 15)
  - Wall, Virginia, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Ward, Wilfred H., 1959 (Box 15)
  - Wasserman, Felix E., 1958 (Box 15)
  - Wasserman, R.H., 1967 (Box 15)
  - Watson, James D., 1978 (Box 15)
  - Watson, John H.L., 1955-1965 (Box 15)
  - Wayne State University, 1968-1969 (Box 15)
  - Weatherwax, Richard C., 1969 (Box 15)
  - Weber, Friedl, 1958-1960 (Box 15)
  - Weber, Hans H., 1957 (Box 15)
  - Weibull, Claes, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Weidel, Wolf, 1950-1962 (Box 15)
  - Weigert, Martin, 1963, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Weigle, Jean, 1950 (Box 15)
  - Weinberger, Martin, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Weiner, John, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Weinhouse, Sidney, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Wells, Robert D., 1972 (Box 15)
    Loeb, Lawrence
  - Wenrich, D.H., 1953 (Box 15)
  - Werner, Georges, 1950 (Box 15)
  - Western Reserve University, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Weymouth, Lisa A., 1977 (Box 15)
  - White, David C., 1961 (Box 15)
  - Whitehouse, Grant, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Whiting, Phineas W., 1966 (Box 15)
  - Wieland, Albert, 1989 (Box 15)
    In German
  - Wilcox, Wesley, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Wildy, Peter, 1962, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Wilkins, Maurice, 1953 (Box 15)
  - Williams, J.W., 1940 (Box 15)
  - Williams, Robley C., 1945-1960 (Box 15)
  - Willoughby, Carl E., 1954-1955 (Box 15)
  - Wilson, Bright, Jr., 1936 (Box 15)
  - Wilson, Dwight E., Jr., 1960 (Box 15)
  - Wilson, Katherine S., 1977 (Box 15)
    -See also Ser.III, National Institutes of Health
  - Winger, Raef, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Wischnitzer, S., 1955 (Box 15)
  - Wistar Party, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Witkin, Evelyn, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Wittmann, G., 1961 (Box 15)
  - Wodak, John, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Wollman, Elie, 1957-1958, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Wolpers, Carl, 1951-1968 (Box 15)
  - Wood, Norris P. (Box 15)
    -See Ser.I, Feldman, William
  - Wood, Thomas H., 1956, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Wulff, Peter, 1933-1934 (Box 15)
  - Wyckoff, Ralph W.G., 1953-1959 (Box 15)
    -See also Ser.I, Denues, A.R.T.
    -See also Ser.I, Williams, Robley C.
  - Wyeth, Cynthia, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Wyman, Jeffries, 1954, 1971-1972, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Yale University, 1952-1959 (Box 15)
  - Yamamoto, Nobuto, 1957-1978 (Box 15)
  - Yanagida, Mitsuhiro, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Yanofsky, Charles, 1977-1978 (Box 15)
  - Yost, Don M., 1936-1965 (Box 15)
    -See also Ser.I, DeVault, Don
    -See also Ser.I, Stang, Louis G., Jr.
  - Young, B.G., 1965 (Box 15)
  - Yura, Takashi, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Zinder, Norton D., 1961, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Zirkle, Raymond E., 1963 (Box 15)
    -See also Ser.I, University of Chicago
  - Zworykin, Vladimir K., 1942, 1969 (Box 15)
    -See also Ser.I, RCA Laboratories
- Series II. Subject files, 1928-1989; 7 boxes; 3.75 linear feet
  Anderson's bibliography and curriculum vitae; some biographical material about Anderson; newspaper clippings; material about conferences; calendars/daybooks for almost every year from 1941 to 1989 that contain Anderson's brief notes; letters written by colleagues and publishers asking for Anderson's permission to publish electron micrographs taken by him; a guest register used in 1942 and in 1949 at the Marine Biological Laboratory in Woods Hole, Massachusetts; and meeting minutes, agenda, and reports for the Biophysical Society. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - American Microscopical Society, 1954 (Box 16)
    -See also Ser.I, same title
  - American Society for X-Ray and Electron Diffraction, 1941-1946, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Bibliography, 1942-1964 (Box 16)
    -See also Ser.II, Curriculum Vitae
  - Bioelectric Repair and Growth Society (Box 16)
  - Biographical Material, 1947-1986 (Box 16)
  - Biophysical Journal, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Biophysical Society, 7 folders (Box 16)
    - Folder #1, 1955-1958 (Box 16)
    - Folder #2, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Folder #3, Feb. 1960 (Box 16)
    - Folder #4, May 1960-Feb. 1964 (Box 16)
    - Folder #5, Feb.-Dec. 1964 (Box 16)
    - Folder #6, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
    - Folder #7, 1968-1971, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Calendar--Notebook, 1967-1968 (Box 17)
  - Calendars, 1941-1978, 1980-1987, 1989, n.d. (Box 17)
  - California Institute of Technology, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - California Institute of Technology, n.d. (Box 17)
    - Transcripts, 1928-1936 (Box 17)
    - Virus Symposium, 20-22 Mar. 1950 (Box 17)
  - Card--Virus Tree (Seasons Greetings), n.d. (Box 17)
  - "Cell Wall of B"--Sketch (Box 17)
    -See Oversized
  - Chain Letter, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Chemistry Course Examinations, 1930-1940; n.d.; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Clippings, 1942-1985, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Conference on Phage Morphogenesis, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Conference on the Control of Form in Cells, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Congrès International de Microscopie Électronique, 1950 (Box 17)
  - "Cooperative Projects with the Johnson Foundation in Electron Microscopy", 4 Jan. 1950 (Box 17)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1942-1982 (Box 17)
  - Electron Micrographs--Permission Letters, 12 folders (Box 17)
    - Folder #1, A-Be, 1940s-1980s (Box 17)
    - Folder #2, Bi-Bu, 1940s-1980s (Box 17)
    - Folder #3, C-Da, 1940s-1980s (Box 17)
    - Folder #4, De-Go, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #5, Gr-Hi, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #6, Ho-J, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #7, K-L, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #8, M-No, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #9, Nu-Sa, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #10, Sc-Su, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #11, T-Wh, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
    - Folder #12, Wi-Z, 1940s-1980s (Box 18)
  - Electron Microscope Society of America, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Folder #1, 1944-1955 (Box 19)
    - Folder #2, 1956-1961, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Electron Microscopes--H.R. 2874, 1964 (Box 19)
  - Electron Microscopes--H.R. 8664, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Fédération Wilhelm Bernhard, 1987 (Box 19)
  - F-Pili Conference, 1971 (Box 19)
  - German Electron Microscope Society, 1953 (Box 19)
  - Gordon Research Conferences, 1960-1961, 1966 (Box 19)
  - "Ideas for Research", 1959, n.d. (Box 19)
  - The Institute for Cancer Research, 1975, 1980-1983, n.d. (Box 19)
  - International Committee on Nomenclature of Viruses, 1970, n.d. (Box 19)
  - International Conference on Electron Microscopy, 1954, n.d. (Box 19)
    -See also Ser.III, "Preservation of Structure in Dried Specimens"
  - International Congress for Microbiology, 1958 (Box 19)
  - International Council of Scientific Unions, 1966 (Box 19)
  - International Federation of Societies for Electron Microscopy, 1964, 1966 (Box 19)
  - International Organization for Pure and Applied Biophysics, 1966 (Box 19)
  - International Society for Cell Biology, 1961 (Box 19)
  - International Union for Pure and Applied Biophysics, 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - The International Who's Who, 1970-1971 (Box 19)
  - Long Island Biological Association, 1958 (Box 19)
  - Marine Biological Laboratory--Guest Register, 1942, 1949 (Box 20)
    -See also Ser.I, Marine Biological Laboratory
  - "This Matter of Life"--Transcripts, 1960 (Box 20)
  - "Men and Molecules"--Script (Box 20)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1960-1980 (Box 20)
  - Philadelphia Electron Microscopy Society, 1955-1974, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Poems, 1953, n.d. (Box 20)
    -See also Ser.I, The University of North Carolina
  - "Postal Laws and Regulations Pertaining to the Mailing of Bacteriological Specimens" (Box 20)
  - Princeton University, 1968 (Box 20)
  - Protoplasmatologia, 1954, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Schedule, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Short-Lived Isotopes--Bibliography, 1953-1966 (Box 20)
  - Sketches (Unidentified), n.d. (Box 20)
    -See also Oversized
  - Society for General Microbiology, 1949 (Box 20)
    -See also Ser.V, "Report on Visit to England and France, April 1949"
  - Society of American Bacteriologists, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Society of General Physiologists, 1950-1969 (Box 20)
  - Statistical Mechanics--Course Text, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Symposium on the Structure and Function of Cell Membranes, 1969 (Box 20)
  - "Translations of Articles on Microscope", 1941 (Box 20)
  - United States Navy Immunization Record, 1949-1954 (Box 20)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Folder #1, [194-]-1964 (Box 20)
    - Folder #2, 1965-1967 (Box 21)
    - Folder #3, 1968-1969 (Box 21)
    - Folder #4, 1970-1973, n.d. (Box 21)
    - Research Club, 1947-1958, n.d. (Box 21)
  - The University of Texas, 1962 (Box 21)
- Series III. Grant files, 1940-1983; 5 boxes; 1.75 linear feet
  Applications, reports, correspondence, and expenditure statements for various agencies that granted Anderson research money for his laboratories at the University of Pennsylvania's Johnson Foundation and at The Institute for Cancer Research. The United States Office of Naval Research accounts for a large portion of the material. Other granting agencies include the National Cancer Institute, the National Science Foundation, and the United States Atomic Energy Commission. There are two folders of material about the National Research Council's RCA Fellowship that Anderson received in 1940.
  Also in this series are reviews of other people's grant applications that Anderson wrote for various agencies, including the National Institutes of Health, the National Research Council, the National Science Foundation, and the United States Atomic Energy Commission. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - American Cancer Society, 1959-1960 (Box 22)
  - National Advisory Allergy and Infectious Diseases Council, 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - National Cancer Institute, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Folder #1, 1975-1978 (Box 22)
    - Folder #2, 1979-1983 (Box 22)
  - The National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, Inc., 1953 (Box 22)
  - Reviews, 11 folders (Box 22)
    Wilson, Katherine S.
    - Folder #1, 1959-1967 (Box 22)
    - Folder #2, 1967-1968 (Box 22)
    - Folder #3, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
    - Folder #4, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Folder #5, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Folder #6, 1969-1971 (Box 23)
    - Folder #7, 1971-1972 (Box 23)
    - Folder #8, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Folder #9, 1973-1975 (Box 23)
    - Folder #10, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Folder #11, 1975, 1978, n.d. (Box 23)
  - National Research Council, 3 folders (Box 24)
    - RCA Fellowship. Folder #1, 1940-Oct. 1941 (Box 24)
      See also Ser.I, LaMer, Victor K.
    - RCA Fellowship. Folder #2, Nov. 1941-1944, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Review, 1941-1943, 1953 (Box 24)
      Rhoads, Jonathan E.
  - National Science Foundation, 8 folders (Box 24)
    - Folder #1, 1958-Apr. 1959 (Box 24)
    - Folder #2, May 1959-1961 (Box 24)
    - Folder #3, 1962 (Box 24)
    - Folder #4, Jan.-Mar. 1963 (Box 24)
    - Folder #5, May 1963-1966 (Box 24)
    - Folder #6, 1970-1978 (Box 24)
    - Reviews. Folder #1, 1954-1970 (Box 24)
    - Reviews. Folder #2, 1970-1974, n.d. (Box 24)
  - United States. Atomic Energy Commission, 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Folder #1, 1949-1954 (Box 25)
    - Folder #2, 1955-1957 (Box 25)
    - Review, 1954 (Box 25)
  - United States. Office of Naval Research, 9 folders (Box 25)
    - Folder #1, 1946-Mar. 1948 (Box 25)
    - Folder #2, Apr.-Nov. 1948 (Box 25)
    - Folder #3, Jan. 1949-May 1950 (Box 25)
    - Folder #4, May 1950-Jul. 1951 (Box 25)
    - Folder #5, Aug. 1951-May 1953 (Box 25)
    - Folder #6, Jun. 1953-Mar. 1954 (Box 25)
    - Folder #7, Apr. 1954-1955 (Box 25)
    - Folder #8, 1956-1969 (Box 26)
    - Folder #9, 1960-1961, n.d. (Box 26)
  - United States. Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1946, n.d. (Box 26)
- Series IV. Works by Anderson, 1943-1985; 14 boxes; 6.5 linear feet